The 2026 Tiny Desk Contest is presented
2026 年 Tiny Desk 大赛
by Capital 1 and supported by Rivian.
由 Capital 1 主办，Rivian 赞助。
Big dreams, tiny desk
远大的梦想，小小的桌面
work of art.
艺术品。
&gt;&gt; Work of art.
艺术作品。   是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
。
Walk into the gallery like [__] I am
走进画廊，就像个女王，我就是
the arsha. Walk into the gallery like
阿尔莎。 走进画廊，就像个
[__] I am the ar show. I walk into the
女王，我就是这场艺术展的主角。 我走进
gallery like [__] I am the art show.
画廊，就像个女王，我就是这场艺术展本身。
Like [__] I am the ar show. Like [__]
就像婊子一样，我就是AR秀。 就像婊子一样，
I am the me. Walk into the gallery like
我就是我。 走进画廊，就好像
I deserve a fee. I pay way too much
我应该获得报酬一样。 我太在意
attention to what people thought of me.
别人对我的看法了。
I walk I walk into the gallery like I
我走进画廊，感觉自己
deserve it all. I need tens and tens and
配得上这一切。 我需要来自
tens from judges all across the I need a
各地法官的十分满分，我需要
seat at the table for me and my homies.
为我和我的兄弟们争取一个席位。
I need all the labels to know me. Boy,
我需要所有标签来了解我。 老兄，
I'm fine as [__] and I kill [__] Luigi
我状态好极了，而且杀人如麻。 路易吉
man black boy hates like a peace never
男人黑人男孩恨透了和平，从未有过
client yours overdrafted. Black boy
客户透支。 黑人男孩
hates like a body getting better over
恨得就像身体随着
time. I'm manifested everything I ever
时间推移而逐渐好转一样。 我
wanted. My whole damn career been going
梦想成真了。 我整个职业生涯都乱
crazy cuz of my paranoid cuz of my
成一团，都是因为我
brothers. I'm buzzing like a nom.
兄弟们让我变得疑神疑鬼。 我兴奋得像个小零食。
Buzzing like cussing a neo-Nazi. I might
嗡嗡作响，就像在咒骂新纳粹分子。 我可能像
buzzing like Cynthia Reaver. If you're
辛西娅·里弗一样兴奋不已。 如果你
homophobic, bet it stings to watch me.
恐同，那看到我肯定很不舒服。
I'm black and I'm buy and I'm better as
我是黑人，我是白人，而且我比别人强
well. My boyfriend is white but he
。 我男朋友是白人，但他长得
pretty as hell. Imagine you hate me and
帅极了。 想象一下，你恨我，而
I'm just over here loving myself. Tiny
我却在这里自恋不已。 小
desk. I know this seems a bit conceited
桌子。 我知道这听起来有点自恋，
but I really used to hate myself. So the
但我以前真的很讨厌自己。 所以这
song's for people who need it. Okay.
首歌是献给那些需要它的人。 好的。
&gt;&gt; Wow. That's why I walk. I walk. I
哇。 这就是我走路的原因。 我步行。
&gt;&gt; Well, that's why I walk.
这就是我走路的原因。
That's why I walk into the gallery like
所以，我走进画廊的时候就像在说：“
[__] I am the show. I walk into the
老娘就是全场焦点！” 我走进
gallery like [__] I am the show. I walk
画廊，就像个女王，我就是全场的焦点。 我
into the gallery like [__] I am the art
走进画廊，就像个女王，我就是这场艺术
show. Like [__] I am the show. Like
展本身。 我就是这场秀的主角，婊子。 就像个
[__] I am the walk into the gallery
婊子一样，我走进画廊
like I'm the captain now they want to
就像我是船长一样，现在他们想
track them down. I earn my strikes. I
找到他们。 我的失误都是靠实力挣来的。 我
got my captain gown. Used to think about
拿到舰长服了。 过去我总是想着
what people thought about me all the
别人怎么看我
time. Now I walk up in the NPR like all
。 现在我走进NPR，感觉这一切都像是
of this is mine. I'm unapologetically
我的一样。 我毫不掩饰地做我
myself. I won't apologize. Jay says
自己。 我不会道歉。  Jay
saying sorry is for a sorry [__] and
说道歉是给一个可怜虫准备的，这句话
changed my life. I had a million things
改变了我的人生。 我
I changed about myself. Now I can't even
改变了自己很多方面。 现在我连
find one. Too many people on three steps
一个都找不到。 太多人走在
ahead. I get [__] up my chest like I'm
前面三步远。 我感觉胸口像灌了铅一样难受，好像要
stopping. I'm not in bed but I'm so
停下来似的。 我虽然不在床上，但却完全
locked in. No intermission but I'm show
沉浸其中。没有中场休息，但我势必会成为全场焦点
stopping. I used to be atheist back in
。 我以前是无神论者
the day. I was getting appraise but I'm
。 我得到了一些评价，但我
no prophet. Huh? Look at me now. I got a
并非先知。 嗯？ 看看我现在。 我
hit on my hand like Chris Brown. Walk in
手上像克里斯·布朗一样被打了一拳。
a gallery like I'm on salary. This is
像领固定工资的人一样走进画廊。 今年
the year that you about to find out
你就会明白了，
[__]
兄弟。
&gt;&gt; Wo. That's why I walk. I walk.
哇。 这就是我走路的原因。 我步行。
&gt;&gt; Wo. That's why I walk.
哇。 这就是我走路的原因。
Wow. That's why I walk. I walk I
哇。 这就是我走路的原因。 我
That's why I walk into the gallery like
走进画廊，就像个
[__] I am the art show. I walk into the
女王，我就是艺术展本身。 我走进
gallery like [__] I am the show. I walk
画廊，就像个女王，我就是全场的焦点。 我
into the gallery like [__] I am the
走进画廊，就像个女王，我就是全场的焦点
show. Like [__] I am the show. Like
。 我就是这场秀的主角，婊子。 就像
[__] I am the [__] I am the Y'all make
婊子一样，我就是婊子，我就是你们，
some noise for this band one time.
为这支乐队欢呼一次吧。
We got Jay Analog and Tomahawk Jones on
我们邀请了 Jay Analog 和 Tomahawk Jones 加入
NPC.
NPC。
We got King Key and Dana Harper on
我们请到了 King Key 和 Dana Harper 担任
vocals.
主唱。
On horn, we got Jordan Carr, ladies and
女士们先生们，我们请到了乔丹·卡尔来为大家介绍节目
gentlemen.
。
ladies and gentlemen.
女士们先生们，我们请到了尼克·罗特·豪斯担任打击乐手。
Make some noise for Emery one time on
为埃默里
the drums.
敲鼓欢呼一下。
ladies and gentlemen.
女士们先生们，独一无二的吉他手是穆拉伯爵。
On bass, we got KJ Gray. Ladies and
贝斯手是KJ Gray。 女士们
gentlemen,
先生们，
and I need y'all to make so so much
我需要你们大声欢呼！
noise. This is the man that has
这位音乐人
musically directed every one of these
负责了所有这些
submissions. On Keys, we got Cinton
参赛作品的音乐指导。 在 Keys 乐队，我们请到了 Cinton
Gray. Ladies and gentlemen,
Gray。 女士们先生们，
oh [__] I'm I'm Cameron Mloud. Hey
哦，天哪，我是卡梅隆·姆劳德。 大家好
y'all.
。
Um, so there's a few rules to a cure for
嗯，治疗
paranoia show. We don't have time to go
妄想症的节目有一些规则。 我们没有时间一一讲解
through all of them, but I am just going
，但我会快速地、非常
cool real quick if that's cool.
酷地讲解一下那个很棒的。
Everybody do me a favor. Look to your
大家帮我个忙。 先看看
left, then look to your right, and then
左边，再看看右边，然后
we're going to run it back because I
我们再来一遍，因为我
know some of y'all ain't looked the
知道你们有些人没往
right way. I I saw it. It's okay.
正确的方向看。 我看到了。 没关系。
Everybody look to your left. Look to
大家看向左边。
your right again. Look to your left and
再往右边看一看。 再向左看，
your right one more time. and realized
向右看。 然后意识到，
[__] looking at you. Right? So
盯着你的既不是他们两个混蛋，也不是你。 正确的？ 所以，
the whole point of a care for paranoia
关注妄想症的全部意义
show is to understand that ain't nobody
就在于理解，没有人会像你一样
thinking about you like you thinking
思考你
about you. Amen.
自己。 阿门。
That's that's rule number one. So if you
这是第一条规则。 所以，如果你
want to jump around, if you want to
想蹦蹦跳跳，如果你想
dance, if you want to hoop, holla, do
跳舞，如果你想玩呼啦圈，那就大声喊出来，去做吧
it. If you want to speak in tongues,
。 如果你想说方言，
then let's just form a circle around
那就让我们围成一个圈把他/
that person. We don't we don't want to
她围起来。
disrupt the flow if the spirit is in
如果神灵在
this room. Amen.
这个房间里，我们不想打断它的运行。 阿门。
&gt;&gt; Amen. With that being said, everybody
阿门。 话虽如此，大家
say left brain.
都说左脑更重要。
&gt;&gt; Left brain.
左脑。
&gt;&gt; Everybody say right brain.
大家都说是右脑。
&gt;&gt; Right brain.
右脑。
&gt;&gt; Everybody go left brain. Right brain.
大家都用左脑思考。 右脑。
&gt;&gt; Left brain. Right brain.
左脑。 右脑。
&gt;&gt; Everybody go left brain. Right brain. No
大家都用左脑思考。 右脑。 没
brain.
脑子。
&gt;&gt; Left brain. Right brain. No brain.
左脑。 右脑。 没脑子。
&gt;&gt; Everybody go left brain. Right brain. No
大家都用左脑思考。 右脑。 没
brain.
脑子。
&gt;&gt; Left brain. Right brain. No brain.
左脑。 右脑。 没脑子。
&gt;&gt; Everybody go left brain. Right brain. No
大家都用左脑思考。 右脑。 没
brain.
脑子。
&gt;&gt; Left brain. Right brain. No brain.
左脑。 右脑。 没脑子。
&gt;&gt; Left brain. Right brain. No brainer. I
左脑。 右脑。 这还用想吗？ 我
lost my mind. Not complaining. Go
疯了。 我不是在抱怨。 去！去！去
go go.
。
Wa. Everybody go left brain. Right
哇。 大家都用左脑思考。
brain. No brain. Left brain. Right. No
右脑。 没脑子。 左脑。 正确的。 决不
way.
。
&gt;&gt; Left, right bra, no brainer. I lost all
左边，右边胸罩，这还用说吗。 我把所有的钱都花光了，
my n I got my beat on in the gym. I got
我在健身房里狠狠地揍了我一顿。
my beat off YouTube. What's the way you
我的伴奏是从YouTube上找的。
talk when you talk to him? Look it all
你跟他说话的方式是怎样的？ 看看
on the wall. Got a screw loose. About to
墙上的那些东西。 螺丝松了。 即将
drop a whole tape made. I don't like
发布一整盘磁带。 我不喜欢
your song cuz I like me. It's a wet
你的歌，因为我喜欢我自己。 这是一场湿身
t-shirt contest. I'm dripped out tight.
T恤大赛。 我浑身湿透了。
I don't write no songs. I'm a lefty. Got
我不写歌。 我是左撇子。 就像有
a ghost with me like dick cage. I write
个鬼魂跟着我，就像个小鸡鸡笼。 我用
my left brain. I'm not gay no more. I'm
左脑写作。 我不再是同性恋了。 我
just insane. A white band, but I'm no
简直疯了。 一条白色的带子，但我无处可去
place. I'm a spot so alive in my own
。 我的名字本身就是一个充满活力的地方
name. I don't fall in love with my role
。 我不会爱上我的角色
play.
扮演。   妈的
Oh [__] Sorry. Left brain, right brain,
。 对不起。 左脑、右脑、
no brain.
无脑。
&gt;&gt; Left brain, right brain, no brain. Left
左脑、右脑、无脑。
brain, right brain, no brainer. I lost
左脑，右脑，这还用想吗？ 我疯了
my mind. Not complaining. Go leftrain,
。 我不是在抱怨。 左脑、
right brain, no brain. Left, right, no
右脑、无脑。 左，右，没有
brain. Left brain, right bra, no
大脑。 左脑，右胸罩，这还
brainer. I lost my mind. Nah. Left,
用想吗？ 我疯了。 不。 左脑，
right, brain. Going back and forth.
右脑。 来回走动。
Brain split down to the apple core. Such
大脑裂开，只剩下苹果核。 真是自大狂
a piss ego. I'm a savage. Got two wheels
。 我是个野蛮人。 我身上装了两个轮子
in me. I'mma feed the bad [__] I'm a
。 我要喂饱那个坏女人。 我是一只
big bad wolf. Yeah, I'm about to blow
大灰狼。 是的，我马上就要冲出
outside your door. N joke. I be kind of
你的门外了。  N 笑话。 我
lame sometimes, but I can't change. No
有时候挺没劲的，但我改不了。
more. When I was in the third grade, I
不再。 我上三年级的时候，
thought that I was straight. Go go go
以为自己是异性恋。 走走走，
[__] I'm just playing back my [__]
兄弟，我只是在重温我的胡言乱语，
mad I be with my dog pissing on my
气急败坏，我和我的狗在我的
territory be getting tense it don't
地盘上撒尿，变得紧张起来，
matter about the category I got this on
类别什么的都无所谓，我掌控着一切，像疯子一样
the count going crazy as a crazy myness
疯狂，我的
is auditory way that brain right brain
听觉方式，大脑右脑，
no brainer I lost my mind
无需动脑，我失去了理智，
&gt;&gt; I could use a
我需要
smoke
抽根烟，我的
&gt;&gt; I mean I know life is too short but
意思是，我知道生命太短暂，但
I get that. Like
我明白这一点。
&gt;&gt; I know life is too short, but at this
我知道人生苦短，但到了这个
point,
地步，
&gt;&gt; you ain't going to hear me complaining.
你不会听到我抱怨了。
&gt;&gt; Look, cuz I mean this is America. This
你看，这里可是美国。 这太
is embarrassing. This is only the
尴尬了。 这仅仅是个
beginning. We need to take the whole
开始。 我们需要把整个
country and put it in rice and then
国家都放进米里，然后
reset the factory settings. We need an
恢复出厂设置。 我们或许需要一场
apocalypse probably. Oddly enough, I
世界末日。 奇怪的是，我
think even a rapture here wouldn't
觉得即使世界末日来临也
suffice. If Jesus came back to this
无济于事。 如果耶稣重返
planet, they'd see he was black and then
地球，人们会发现他是黑人，然后
say he was the antichrist. They keep on
说他是反基督者。 他们一直在
talking. Let's get to the bottom line.
说话。 让我们直奔主题。
You spreading hate in a nation
你在一个经济萧条的国家散播仇恨
demonetized. Don't be surprised when
。 当
your head got a dollar sign. Talk out
你的脑袋上冒出一个美元符号时，不要感到惊讶。 别再说“
the side of your I apologize. What was
我道歉”了。
the race of the two boys in Coline?
科林镇那两个男孩是什么种族？   这只是个
Rhetorical question, but I'm sure you
反问句，但我相信你
got it white. I won't be silenced. I put
买到的肯定是白色的。 我不会保持沉默。 我冒了生命危险
my neck on the line. Lie as a black
。 谎称自己是黑人
pilot. And yes, I'm qualified. Lead a
飞行员。 是的，我符合资格。 带领
room. Bombs dropping. Lead a room. Okay.
全场。 炸弹落下。 带领全场。 好的。
Bombs dropping. Lead a room. Okay. Bombs
炸弹落下。 带领全场。 好的。 炸弹
dropping. Lead the room. Say left brain.
落下。 引领全场。 就说是左脑吧。
Right brain. No brain.
右脑。 没脑子。
&gt;&gt; Left brain. Right brain. No brain.
左脑。 右脑。 没脑子。
&gt;&gt; Left brain. Right brain. No brain. I
左脑。 右脑。 没脑子。 我
lost my mind. I complain and go left
疯了。 我抱怨，然后就用左脑思考
brain. Right brain. No brain. Left
。 右脑。 没脑子。
brain. Right brain.
左脑。 右脑。
That brain right nobrainer. I lost my
那简直是显而易见的。 我疯了
mind. I complained. I lost my mind. I
。 我投诉了。 我疯了。 我
lost my mind.
疯了。
Thank y'all. Appreciate it.
谢谢大家。 谢谢。
Um, so last year
嗯，去年
I committed to posting a new rap every
我承诺一年365天每天都要发布一首新的说唱歌曲
single day for the entire year.
。
&gt;&gt; And and did
然后，
Oh, what book you reading? Is that the
哦，你在读什么书？ 那是收录
book of all the verses?
所有诗句的书吗？
&gt;&gt; 165.
165.
&gt;&gt; 3650 on Amazon.com. Uh,
亚马逊网站上的 3650。 呃，
I started off the year with
年初的时候我只有不到
barely 10,000 followers. ended the year
1万名粉丝。 年底时
with over 375,000 followers. And I don't
拥有超过 37.5 万粉丝。 我不
know if y'all know, but the halfway mark
知道你们知不知道，
of the year is uh 183. And you probably
一年过半是183年。你们可能
do know that because you know you're
知道，因为你们
good at math. I'm not. Uh I know that
数学很好。 我不是。 嗯，我知道现在已经
it's the halfway mark because on day
过半了，因为在第
183, my mom's had texted me and she
183 天，我妈妈给我发短信
congratulated me on being halfway
祝贺我
through the year. Uh all through the
一年已经过半了。
year last year, she would always just be
去年一整年，她总是说：
like, "I love your dedication. you you
“我喜欢你的投入。你
said you were gonna do something and
说过你会做某件事，
you're doing it and it's and you're
你现在正在做，而且做得很好
making it work.
。
&gt;&gt; Shout out to mama.
向妈妈致敬。”
Um,
嗯，就在
shortly after she had sent me that text,
她给我发了那条短信后不久，
she had suffered a minor heart attack.
她就突发轻微心脏病。
And when I was up at the hospital with
我在医院陪
her, the entire time I was at the
她的时候，
hospital, she was like, "Did you do your
她一直问我：“你写完你的那段
verse? Make sure you go do your verse.
歌词了吗？” 记得去完成你的那段歌词。
Make sure you do your verse." Um
确保你唱完你的那段。”​​嗯，
and uh yeah, she unfortunately passed
还有，很不幸，她
four days later in her sleep. But uh I
四天后在睡梦中去世了。但是，我之所以先
the reason why I mentioned the following
提到下面这些
first before that, I just want to say
，是因为
that I had every reason to quit and I
我有很多理由放弃，也
had every reason not to continue, but I
有很多理由不再继续，但我
knew that would make my mom so sad if
知道如果那是我放弃的原因，我妈妈会非常伤心
that was the reason why, you know. Um,
。嗯，
so I say all that to say, if a little
所以我说这些是想说，如果一个患有
black boy with mental illness in the
精神疾病、正经历丧母之痛的小黑男孩
middle of a dead mom arc can commit to
都能坚持
himself for a full year, there's no
一整年，那么
reason that everybody in this room can't
在座的各位也完全可以做到
do whatever it is that they set their
他们下定
mind to times 10. You know what I'm
决心要做的事情，而且可以做得更好。你们明白我的
saying?
意思吗？
Um,
嗯，
so,
所以，不管
uh, whether your mom is here or not,
你们的妈妈是否在这里，不管
whether your mom's with us or not, none
你们的妈妈是否和我们在一起，如果没有
our mom. So, on a count of three, can we
妈妈，我们谁都不会站在这里。所以，数到三，我们一起
all say thank you, mama? One, two,
说声谢谢，妈妈。一，二，
three. Thank you, mama.
三。谢谢妈妈。
&gt;&gt; Period.
句号。是的
&gt;&gt; Yeah, absolutely. Um,
，当然。嗯
well, speaking of persevering, we lost
，说到坚持，我们输了
three times
三次，
and still made it up here. So, I think
还是设法来到了这里。所以，我觉得
it's only appropriate for us to go back
我们应该回到
to the very first tiny decimation that
最初那
got us noticed in the first place. Is
场让我们被注意到的微小破坏。这样可以吗
that all right?
？好
&gt;&gt; Cool. Cool. Cool.
。好。好。
Look, look. And I say, I'm going to get
听着，听着。我说，我先去喝点
water first.
水。
That's right.
没错。我告诉
&gt;&gt; Let me tell you like I'm so unbothered
你，我现在一点也不在意。我现在一点也不在意。我现在一点也不在意。
unbothered. So if you got problem then
所以如果你有什么问题，那就
don't bother coming around. I'm so
别来烦我。我现在一点也不在意。我现在一点也不在意。我
unbothered right now. I'm so unbothered
现在一点也不在意。
right now. I'm so unbothered. So if you
所以如果你
got problem then don't bother coming
有什么问题，那就别来烦我
around. Mace to the face had a verse hit
。脸上被喷了辣椒水，歌词像
eagle alter how you worshiping a [__]
鹰一样飞过，你是怎么崇拜一个
making a wave you can surf it while the
掀起波澜的黑鬼的？你可以冲浪，而
rains to the plane dropping bird [__] on
雨水却落在飞机上，飞机在你们这些黑鬼身上扔鸟粪，
you [__] bird it's a plane it's a
鸟，那是一架飞机，那是个
[__] and a cake got a lighter in a tank
黑鬼，还有一块蛋糕，油箱里插着打火机，
cuz I learned this if it ain't serving
因为我学到了这一点。 对
you you better burn bridge looking
你没用，你最好断绝关系，别再浪费
energy up and they deserve it ain't
精力了，他们活该。
working for you don't you put the work
对你没用，你不努力吗？
in you can't win together that defeat
你们不可能一起赢，那样就违背了
the purpose subitted but they better
初衷。他们最好别
ain't no [__] and my piece I'm allergic
废话，我
to them they be acting funny well it's
对他们过敏，他们行为怪异。好吧，那些
curtains to them [__] that can show me
能让我见识到
really burns [__] food and only
真正厉害的家伙就此作罢。婊子，食物，唯一的
motivation money where it surface moment
动力，金钱，在表面，当
I'm satisfied hungry so my Perks
我感到满足和饥饿时，我的福利在
improving rather independence from it.
提升，而不是独立。
If it's codependent and I put it on a
如果这是相互依赖，我把它放在
bonus [__] I ain't going to end up when
奖励上，兄弟，我不会让
I let them in the finish what I see I'm
他们进来，结束我看到的一切。我
sac my rhyme but got spells in it. Not
牺牲我的韵脚，但里面有咒语。不是
that it's magic.
魔法。
&gt;&gt; Actually an alchemist. Not that it
实际上是炼金术士。但这并不
matters. Creating matters don't create
重要。创造重要，不要为了
to matter. My verse is a horcrux. A bad
重要而创造。我的诗句是一个魂器。一个邪恶的
cadabra. And I'm so unbothered right
卡达布拉。我现在很无忧
now. I'm so unbothered right now. I'm so
。我现在很无忧。我现在很
unbothered. So if you got problem then
无忧。所以如果你有 有问题就
don't bother coming around. I'm so
别来了。我
unbothered right now. He's so unthe
现在一点都不烦。他
right now. I'm so bothered. So if you
现在也很烦。我很烦。所以如果你
got problem then don't bother coming
有问题就别来了。我很烦。所以如果
I'm so bothered. So if you got proud
你很骄傲，
then no mother coming around. Wo
那就没人会来。呜呜，
wo I'm so un bothered. So if you got
我一点都不烦。所以如果你很
proed and no mother coming around.
骄傲，也没人会来。
I guess before we get out of here I
我想在我们离开这里之前，我
should let y'all know what cure for
应该告诉你们“
paranoia actually means. Right. So it's
妄想症疗法”到底是什么意思。对。之所以
called cure for paranoia on account of
叫“妄想症疗法”，是因为
10 years ago I was placed on medication
10年前我开始服用治疗
for bipolar depression and paranoid
双相抑郁症和偏执型
schizophrenia.
精神分裂症的药物。
But it turned out that the music was way
但结果发现，音乐
more therapeutic than the medication
比药物的疗效好得多
was. Right? So I created this band, this
。对吧？所以我创建了这个乐队，这个
brand, this movement called Cure for
品牌，这个运动，叫做“
Paranoia. Cuz creating music with these
妄想症疗法”。因为和这些人一起创作音乐
people is my therapy. So hopefully the
就是我的疗愈方式。所以希望
music we create could be therapy for
我们创作的音乐也能成为其他人的疗愈方式
other people as well. You know,
。你们知道，
thank y'all.
谢谢大家。
Well, well
好了好了，
y'all, please take your meds though.
各位，请收拾你们的 吃药啊。
This is this is not me saying paranoid.
我不是说我妄想症。
Everybody quit your medication quick.
大家赶紧停药。
Get off. No. My god. Today. No. That'd
停药。不。我的天。今天就停。不。那太
be crazy. That'd be how I end up on
疯狂了。那样我就要上
news. Somebody just somebody run up on
新闻了。有人会在
me at the end of a show like he told ME
节目结束的时候冲过来，好像他叫我别
NOT TO TAKE MY MED.
吃药似的。
&gt;&gt; HE TOLD ME NOT TO take my
他叫我别吃药，就像
&gt;&gt; a broken record that ain't broke no
一张坏掉的唱片，根本没打破任何
record.
纪录。
&gt;&gt; Now let me formulate my own opinion.
现在让我自己说说我的看法。你
&gt;&gt; Mad cuz you sleep, but he ain't show no
生气是因为你睡觉，但他一点
effort.
努力都没有。
&gt;&gt; That's pillow talk but ain't got no
那只是枕边细语，没有实际
commitment.
行动。
&gt;&gt; No commitment.
没有实际行动。
&gt;&gt; He ain't the spokesperson for mental
他不是精神
illness.
疾病的代言人。
If anything, this [__] out his mind.
要我说，这家伙疯了。
Boy, ain't you sober out here acting
小子，你清醒着在这儿装出一副
spiritual? That's just for show. I seen
精神导师的样子？那只是装腔作势。我看到
him snorting lines. Oh, I guess that's
他吸食可卡因。哦，我猜这就是
the cure for paranoia. Positive
治疗妄想症的良方。
affirmations on Facebook while he act
在脸书上写些积极的自我肯定，同时装出一副很
important. I heard this [__] up a D and
重要的样子。我听到这家伙吸了点毒品，还
act like he too good. Talking about how
装出一副高人一等的样子。说什么
he going to lead a city. What a [__]
他要领导一座城市。什么鬼？ 一个被
overrated under influence. Lost my
高估的、嗑药嗑嗨了的家伙。我
weight. I done got back to throwing
瘦了。我又开始像以前那样，用
shade where I throw grenades when I blow
我那招来招摇撞骗的本事，就像扔手榴弹一样，
a space and you just can't do it. Can
你根本招架不住。
you play ho? Let's do it. I walk a block
你会玩吗？来啊。我走在街上，
a flame background music. I go hard in
背景音乐像火焰一样燃烧。我他妈的在
the [__] pain, [__] I'm a
痛苦中拼命，兄弟。我就是个
show. Go ahead, take a picture of [__]
表演家。来吧，像背着个大块头一样拍张照吧，
like a piggy back with a gizzy at cuz
因为
I'm just being frank even before Kane. I
我比凯恩还坦率。我
see plenty mask too many cap. I see it
见过太多戴着面具的人，太多只会吹牛的人。
all in your face. Cut my [__] out the
你的脸上什么都看得出来。像用
picture like some kitty scissors. I'm
猫剪刀一样把我的兄弟从照片里剪掉。我已经
written and releasing on my inhibition.
写好了，正在释放我的压抑。
I can't listen to you if you only listen
如果你只听我的，我就听不进你的
to me. Friend the neighborhood [__]
。和街区的兄弟们交朋友。
You getting by with sick fingers. I
你靠着一双灵巧的手混日子。我
ain't talking private. Say that I'm a
不是在说私事。说我是个
profit. I ain't throwing out my shoulder
赚钱的。我不会扭伤肩膀，
but I'm going out of pocket. And I ain't
但我会自掏腰包。我不会
fing up for no one I can roast papa
为任何人犯错，我可以把老爸烤得
sideway
焦头烂额。
you guys on anyway let me pray
你们都还在吗？让我祈祷
meditation yo I can go out the window
冥想一下。
with your partner if you [__] with
如果你敢动我的名册，我可以和你的搭档一起从窗户跳出去。
the roster I came along from the hol
我从度假胜地来到这里，靠着
living when I pay with imposter and I
冒名顶替者的生活过日子，我
ain't going back I ain't going back and
不会回头。我不会
forth with you can't afford I didn't pay
和你来回扯皮，你负担不起。我没花钱去
to pay attention so they can't ignore it
关注，所以他们不能忽视我。我以前被当成
in the forest till I hit the ground
森林里倒下的树，直到我重新振作起来。
running now they hit a noise god damn it
现在他们听到了动静，该死的，
I'm hopping out the bottom of the water
我正从水底跳出来，
while I'm conceding [__] running in
同时承认那些在
the pool meaning that it really ain't as
泳池​​里奔跑的家伙，这意味着事情并没有
deep thinking that you see got to reach
你想象的那么复杂。你得努力去争取，而不是空想。
instead of wishing it was [__] I'm the
我是
tortoise and the racing [__] nestled
乌龟，那些赛跑的家伙依偎
in. I was dealing with depression to
在我身边。我曾经饱受
depression hit now just a couple seconds
抑郁症的折磨，现在只需几秒钟就能赢得
for my second win. Now I'm dripping like
我的第二场胜利。现在我像个
a positive. I don't even need my water
正能量的源泉一样闪耀。我甚至不需要我的水
vis.
视光。
That kid count.
那孩子算数。
See, before I was cure for paranoia, I
你看，在我治愈妄想症之前，我
used to go up to the mall and sell my
曾经去商场卖我的
CDs to people by the name of that kid
CD。 就叫那个孩子吧
count.
。
And now, and now I'm getting my cake up.
现在，现在我要大赚一笔了。分手的时候，我
Had to break through when I break up all
必须突破重围。
at the same damn time. Mascara, makeup,
睫毛膏、化妆、
sex, I was sick, but it's gone like a
性，我曾经病入膏肓，但现在就像
goddamn vine. When I'm pissed off, make
藤蔓一样消失了。当我生气的时候，我的
more moves than a tick tock dance.
行动比滴答舞还要猛烈。
Work it out, gang up, flexing in the
解决问题，团结起来，对着
mirror, too.
镜子炫耀。
&gt;&gt; Hey, and y'all look confused. Y that you
嘿，你们看起来很困惑。为什么你们
had this [__] all figured out. It's got
把这一切都想明白了？
some news for you. I tell the truth,
我得告诉你们一些消息。我说的是实话
y'all. [__] working so Dallas observe
。兄弟们都在努力，达拉斯都在关注
on your work. Ain't no news on the new
你们的工作。没有什么新消息
[__] Sounding like I already made it as
。听起来我已经作为
a crew mindset. Justin Timberlake. I'm
一个团队成功了。贾斯汀·汀布莱克。我是
Jenny Jackson titty at the Super Bowl.
超级碗上的珍妮·杰克逊。
When I pop it on, you [__] start to
当我露出它的时候，你们这些家伙就开始
lose control. Ain't no way I can't
失去控制。我不可能不靠
self. Ain't going to say no dangle
自己来维持整个竞选活动。我不会透露任何人的
names, but hey folks, change [__] can't
名字，但是嘿，伙计们，改变一下吧。 不可能
be. I still got love for my [__] Just
。我依然爱我的兄弟们。只是
a shame I can't really [__] with you.
可惜我不能真的和你一起玩。
Last night I said some scissor. I just
昨晚我说了些废话。我
focus on the good days now. Hit
现在只专注于美好的日子。感觉不
different. I'm getting my cake up. Had
一样了。我正在努力赚钱。我必须
to break through when I break up all the
突破，因为我总是分手
time. Mascara, makeup, sex. I'm a sassic
。睫毛膏、化妆、性。我曾经很性感
seconds, but it's gone like a goddamn
，但就像该死的藤蔓一样消失了
vine. When I'm pissed off, make more
。当我生气的时候，我会
moves in the tick tock dance moves
在滴答作响的舞步中做出更多
crazy.
疯狂的动作。
Wait up. Work it out. G up. Flexing in
等等。解决问题。振作起来。对着
the mirror. So goddamn fine.
镜子炫耀。太他妈帅了。太他
So goddamn fine. Flexing in the mirror.
妈帅了。对着镜子炫耀。
So
太
goddamn fine. Flexing in the mirror. So
他妈帅了。对着镜子炫耀。太他妈帅了
goddamn fine. Flexing in the mirror. If
妈帅了。对着镜子炫耀。如果
you love yourself, can you make some
你爱自己，你能
noise one time?
大声欢呼一次吗？
I don't know it sound like some of y'all
我不知道，听起来你们有些人好像经历了
was going through something. I said if
什么。我说如果
you love yourself and you make some
你爱自己，就
noise one time.
大声欢呼一次。
Look, that's how I'm getting my cake up.
听着， 这就是我搞定一切的方法。
Breakthrough when I break up all the
突破在于我把所有妆容都卸掉，
more moves than a tick tock dance moves
动作比滴答作响的舞蹈还要混乱
in a chaot.
。
Come on.
来吧。
&gt;&gt; Okay, I ain't crying on the camera, so
好吧，我不会在镜头前哭的，所以我们
let's go on. Let's Let's wrap it up.
继续。我们结束吧。
Thank y'all so much. Thank you.
非常感谢大家。谢谢。